The Girl King is a drama, history, romance film directed by Mika Kaurismäki.
A portrait of the brilliant, extravagant Kristina of Sweden, queen from age six, who fights the conservative forces
that are against her ideas to modernize Sweden and who have no tolerance for her awakening sexuality.
Kristina, played by Malin Buska.
Countess Ebba Sparre, played by Sarah Gadon.
Chancellor Axel Oxenstierna, played by Michael Nyqvist.
Count Johan Oxenstierna, played by Lucas Bryant.
Countess Erika Erksein, played by Laura Birn.
Ambassador Pierre Hector Chanut, played by Hippolyte Girardot.
The Girl King is a 2015 biographical drama about Christina, Queen of Sweden.
It was directed by Mika Kaurismäki and written by Michel Marc Bouchard who, after writing the screenplay for the film, wrote his stage play Christine, La
Reine-Garçon which enjoyed a successful run in 2012 at Montreal's Théâtre du Nouveau Monde and then in English at the Stratford Festival in 2014.
The film premiered at the Montreal World Film Festival.
The film explores themes of marriage proposal, strong
woman, queen, sweden, political negotiations.
The tone is emotional.